online-casinos.com 2019-12-21

# Privacy Policy of the Website Online-Casinos.com

**As of: December 2019**

Trust and reliability are of particular importance for our users. For us, this also includes the protection of personal data, which is one of our primary company principles. We therefore process personal data on our website strictly in accordance with the applicable legal provisions and, in particular, in accordance with the requirements of the [EU General Data Protection Regulation](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN) (hereinafter: GDPR), applicable throughout Europe. We would like to inform you in the following about the processing of personal data carried out by us in accordance with this regulation (see Article 13 of the GDPR). Please read our data privacy statement carefully. 

## 1\. Overview

The following data protection information provides information on the type and scope of the processing of what is known as **personal data**. Personal data is information that is or can be directly or indirectly attributable to your person. 

### What is personal data?

Personal data is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter “data subject”). This includes information such as your name, address, IP address or email address. Information that is not directly associated with your real identity (such as favourite websites or the number of users of a site) is not included.

### What is anonymised data?

Each time you access the content of our website, general information is automatically stored (e.g. number and duration of users of individual sites, etc.). This information is not personal because it does not relate to an identified or identifiable individual, i.e. there is no way we can associate the information with any particular individual. The data is therefore processed in an anonymised form. Information of this kind is gathered for purely statistical purposes and is used by us for the optimisation of our Internet services.

The data processing via our services can **essentially be divided into two categories:**

  * All necessary data will be processed by online-casinos.com for the purpose of providing our **services** , in particular for the operation of our platform. In this way, we can ensure that we offer our visitors the best possible service. If third parties, e.g. partner sites, providers of online gaming, subcontractors, etc. are involved in the provision, your data will be passed on to them to the extent necessary in each individual case.
  * **When the website is accessed** , various pieces of information are exchanged between your device and our server. This may also involve personal data. The information collected in this way is used, among other things, to optimise our website or to display **advertising** in the browser of your device. 

In accordance with the requirements of the GDPR, you have **various rights** which you are able to assert. This includes, among other things, the right to **object** to selected data processing, in particular data processing for advertising purposes. The ability to object is **emphasised** in the printing process. Should you have any questions regarding our data protection information, please feel free to contact us at any time. You will find our contact details below.

As a matter of principle, we process personal data only in accordance with the applicable **statutory storage and safekeeping obligations** or until the respective purpose ceases to apply, or if the processing is no longer required.

## 2\. Name and contact details of data controller and of the data protection officer 

This data protection statement applies to data processing by and to our website www.online-casinos.com. If you have any questions regarding the data protection, please do not hesitate to contact us at the above address, our Data Protection Office, or send us a message at [dataprivacy@online-casinos.com](mailto:dataprivacy@online-casinos.com).

## 3\. Purposes of data processing, legal bases and legitimate interests pursued by online-casinos.com or a third party, and categories of recipients

### 3.1. Accessing our website

When you access our website, the browser used on your device automatically sends information to our website’s server and temporarily stores it in what is known as a log file. We have no influence with respect to this. **The following information** is gathered without any action on your part and stored until it is automatically deleted: 

  * the IP address of the requesting Internet-enabled device, 
  * date and time of access, 
  * the website from which access was made (referrer URL), 
  * your own campaign ID,
  * the browser you are using and, if applicable, the operating system of your internet-enabled computer, as well as the name of your access provider. 

The legal basis for the **processing of your IP address** is Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f of the GDPR. Our legitimate interest follows from the purposes of data collection listed below. At this point, we would like to point out that we cannot deduce your identity from the data collected and that we do not draw any conclusions about your identity.

The IP address of your device and the other data listed above are used by us for the **following purposes** :

  * Ensuring a smooth connection setup,
  * Ensuring our website is convenient to use, 
  * Evaluating the system’s security and stability, as well as 
  * further administrative purposes. 

The data is stored for the duration of the respective session and automatically deleted when the browser is closed. We also use cookies, tracking tools and a CRM system for our website. The exact procedures involved and how their data is used for this purpose are explained in more detail below. 

### 3.2. Data processing via contact form

For customer support purposes, we offer you the option of submitting individual enquiries via our contact form. If you decide to send us an enquiry, we will process the following data:

  * surname and the given name provided,
  * subject of the request,
  * email address provided,
  * the request you have made,
  * IP address of the device used,
  * date and time of the enquiry,

to process your enquiry. The legal basis for this is Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. b) of the GDPR. This processing is necessary in order to process your request as required. The data can be stored in a CRM system. We will delete your enquiries if their storage is no longer necessary. You can object to this processing at any time with **immediate effect**. To do this, you can simply send a brief email to this address: [dataprivacy@online-casinos.com](mailto:dataprivacy@online-casinos.com).

### 3.3. Online presence and website optimisation

#### 3.3.1. YouTube integration

On our website, you will find a wide range of information about gaming. In addition to articles and photos, we also provide informative videos, e.g. in our blog posts. For this purpose, we make use of, on the basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f of the GDPR, integration with YouTube, a service from YouTube LLC. 901 Cherry Ave. San Bruno, CA 94066. USA (hereinafter: “YouTube”). For this purpose, we set a cookie from YouTube whenever you visit a page, which establishes a connection to YouTube’s servers. The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website, such as 

  * Browser type/version,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the page previously visited),
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address), 
  * time of the server request, or
  * website or subpage visited

is transmitted to a YouTube server in the USA, where it is stored. We regard processing for the improvement of our website, by enhancing and complementing content with informative videos, as our legitimate interest. You can **prevent** the installation of cookies in advance by making the appropriate settings in the browser software, or object to this processing by deleting cookies via your browser settings, or [changing](https://myaccount.google.com/privacycheckup/7?utm_source=accounts&utm_medium=callout&utm_campaign=new_privacy_checkup) the corresponding settings in the data protection centre. You will find more detailed information about the collection and use of data by YouTube and Google, and about your rights and options for protecting your privacy, under YouTube’s [privacy policy](https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/addthis-privacy-policy.html).

#### 3.3.2. Cookies – General information 

We use what are known as cookies on our website. Our interest in optimising our website can be deemed to be legitimate within the meaning of the aforementioned provision. Cookies are small files that are automatically created by your browser and stored on your device (laptop, tablet, smartphone, etc.) when you visit our website. Cookies do not cause any damage to your device, nor do they contain any viruses, Trojans or other malware. The cookie stores information that results in conjunction with the specifically used device. This does not mean, however, that we will gain immediate knowledge of your identity. The use of cookies serves to make the use of our services more enjoyable for you. 

#### 3.3.3. Session cookies

When you visit our website, we use what are known as session cookies to identify that you have already visited individual pages on our website. These are deleted automatically after you leave our site. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can, however, configure your browser in such a way that cookies are not stored on your computer, or that a notification appears each time before a new cookie is set. The complete deactivation of cookies can, however, result in reduced functionality of our website, and you may not be able to use all functions on our website. How long cookies are stored for depends on their purpose, and is not the same for everyone. 

#### 3.3.4. Google Analytics 

For the purpose of the needs-based organisation and continuous optimisation of our website, we use the Google Analytics analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter: “Google”) on the basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f) of the GDPR. To this end, **pseudonymised user profiles** are created and cookies are used. The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website, such as 

  * Browser type/version,
  * Device name,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the page previously visited),
  * keywords/specific search enquiry,
  * service provider,
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address), 
  * time of the server request, 

is transmitted to a Google server in the USA, where it is stored. The information is used to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on website activities and to provide additional services related to website and Internet usage for the purpose of market research and the appropriate presentation of these sites. Where appropriate, this information will also be transmitted to third parties if this is legally required, or insofar as third parties process this data on our behalf. Under no circumstances will your IP address be merged with other Google data. The IP addresses are made anonymous so that they **cannot be assigned** (IP masking). You can **object** to this data processing at any time by **preventing** the installation of cookies by setting the browser software accordingly. However, we would like to point out that, in this case, not all functions of our website may be fully usable. You can also prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address), and the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing this [browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). For more information about data protection relating to Google Analytics, please visit the [Google Analytics website](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en). 

#### 3.3.5. AddThis

On our website we use plugins from the service AddThis, a service of AddThis, LLC, 1595 Spring Hill Rd, Suite 300, Vienna, VA 22182, USA (hereinafter “AddThis”) on the basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f of the GDPR. AddThis provides tools for creating and designing websites that make it easier for website visitors to share the current page they are viewing with other Internet users via email or social net-works. AddThis also provides us with tools that help us analyse and improve the use of our website or enable us to address users directly. We regard the aforementioned purposes as our legitimate inter-ests. If you are using an AddThis plugin, your browser will establish a direct connection to the servers of AddThis and the selected social network. The data generated includes:

  * Browser type/version,
  * device name,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the page previously visited),
  * service provider,
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address), 
  * time of the server request, 

This is transferred to the server of AddThis in the USA and processed there. We do not process the data concerned or pass it on to third parties. You can **object** to this data processing and storage by Add-This at any time by **preventing** the installation of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly. You can also prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website, and the processing of this data by AddThis, by deleting the cookie(s) in your browser. In addition, you have the option of deactivating the cookie via an opt-out by clicking this [link](https://datacloudoptout.oracle.com/#optout) and then clicking the “Opt-out” button. You can find more information about the provider’s data protection in the [privacy policy](https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/addthis-privacy-policy.html) from AddThis.

#### 3.3.6. Virtual Web Optimizer

For the purpose of the needs-based organisation and continuous optimisation of our website, we use the analysis service Virtual Web Optimizer, a service from Wingify, Inc., 14th Floor, KLJ Tower North, Netaji Subhash Place, Pitam Pura, Delhi 110034, India (hereinafter “Wingify”) for test purposes on certain pages on the basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f of the GDPR. If the service is used, we set a cookie to obtain valid test results. The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website, such as 

  * Browser type/version,
  * device name,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the page previously visited),
  * keywords/specific search enquiry,
  * service provider,
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address), 
  * time of the server request, 

is transmitted to a Wingify server in India, where it is stored. We have absolutely no way of assigning these anonymous measured values to you, for example by assigning your IP address or by other means. The information is used to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on website activi-ties and to provide additional services related to website and Internet usage for the purpose of market research and the needs-based design of these sites. We regard these purposes as our legitimate inter-ests. If the cookie does not expire at the end of the session, it is available for a maximum of 100 days. 

You can **object** to this data processing at any time by **preventing** the installation of cookies by setting the browser software accordingly. You can also prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address), and the processing of this data by Wingify, by deleting the cookie(s) in your browser.

Further information about Wingify’s cookies can be found in the [provider’s further information](https://vwo.com/knowledge/what-are-the-cookies-stored-by-vwo/) section and the corresponding [privacy policy](https://vwo.com/privacy-policy/).

#### 3.3.7. Maxmind

To provide you with offers and information relevant to your country of access, we use a third-party service – Maxmind, Inc., 14 Spring Street, Suite 3, Waltham, MA 02451 USA. Maxmind provides us with tools that indicate your geolocation, using your IP address, so that we can show you a country-specific page. The legal basis for processing your data is Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f of the GDPR. 

The following data is collected by Maxmind: IP address of the requesting internet-enabled device You can find more detailed information about data protection in the privacy policy of Maxmind. 

#### 3.3.8. Newsletter registration via double-opt-in

We offer all interested persons the opportunity to sign up for our newsletter in order to stay up to date: The recipients will, in particular, be provided with the news posted in the week and a summary of new current bonuses in the market. We use the double opt-in process to confirm that the email address entered actually corresponds to the prospective customer. After the email address is entered, we send you a confirmation link. Your email address will only be included on our mailing list after you click on this confirmation link. We store the information collected during this process only for purposes of documentation and proof. This includes:

  * The email address you provide,
  * The date and time of registration,
  * The date, content and time of the confirmation email,
  * The IP address of the device used for the confirmation,
  * The usage data (e.g. if you opened the Newsletter) and
  * The date and time of your confirmation

The legal basis for this is Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. a of the GDPR. We store this information as long as you are signed up in order to prove the legality of sending the newsletter. In case you unsubscribe from the newsletter, we retain the information for the period specified by law. During this period (usually 10 years from the conclusion of the agreement), the data will only be processed again in case it is required to prove the consent to receive the newsletter. You can withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future. Simply click on the unsubscribe button in the respective e-mail or send a short note by e-mail to [dataprivacy@online-casinos.com.](mailto:dataprivacy@online-casinos.com)

## 4\. Recipients outside the EU

With the exception of the processing operations described under 3.3, we do not pass on your data to recipients based outside of the European Union or the European Economic Area. The processing referred to in 3.3 results in data transfer to the servers of the provider **of web analysis technology** com-missioned by us (see above). Some of these servers are located in the USA. This data transfer takes place strictly in accordance with the principles of the so-called [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome) and on the basis of the so-called [standard contractual clauses](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:L:2010:039:0005:0018:EN:PDF) of the EU Commission. You can obtain a copy of these standard contractual clauses from us. 

## 5\. Storage duration and deletion of data

Your personal data will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of storage no longer applies, or you revoke your consent. In addition, storage can take place if this has been provided for by the Euro-pean or national legislator under EU regulations, laws or other provisions to which the person responsible is subject. If the storage purpose no longer applies, you revoke your consent or a storage period prescribed by the European regulator or another responsible legislator expires, the personal data will be blocked or deleted routinely and in accordance with the statutory provisions, unless there is a need for further storage of the data for the conclusion of a contract or fulfilment of a contract.

## 6\. Your rights 

### 6.1. Overview

In addition to the right to revoke your consent given to us, you are entitled to the following additional rights if the respective legal requirements are met: 

  * Right to information about your personal data stored by us, as per Article 15 of the GDPR,
  * Right to correction of incorrect data or to completion of correct data, as per Article 16 of the GDPR,
  * Right to deletion of your data stored by us, as per Article 17 of the GDPR, 
  * Right to limit the processing of your data, as per Article 18 of the GDPR,
  * Right to data transferability, as per Article 20 of the GDPR.

To assert your rights, a brief notification to our internal Data Protection Office is sufficient. You can reach the office by email at [dataprivacy@online-casinos.com.](mailto:dataprivacy@online-casinos.com)

### 6.2. Right to object

**Under the conditions of Article 21, Paragraph 1 of the GDPR, data processing may be objected to for reasons arising from the specific circumstances of the data subject.**

The **general right to object** mentioned above applies to all processing purposes described in this data privacy statement which are carried out on the basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, lit. f of the GDPR. In contrast to the special right to object to data processing for advertising purposes (see above), we are only obliged under the GDPR to act on a general objection if you provide us with reasons as to why it is so important (e.g. a possible danger to life or health). In addition, you may also contact the regulatory authority which we fall under. 

## 7\. Data security

All data transmitted by you personally, including payment data, is done so using the generally accepted and secure standard SSL (Secure Socket Layer). SSL is a secure and proven standard, which is also used for online banking, for example. You can identify a secure SSL connection, among other things, by the additional “s” on the http (https://…) in the address bar of your browser, or by the lock symbol at the bottom of your browser.

We also use suitable technical and organisational security measures to protect your personal data stored by us against manipulation, partial or complete loss and against unauthorised access by third parties.
